<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>File 1</name>
		<update version="1.1.1">
			<file name="file1.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/drane44/DranesHomebrew/master/user-Drane/file1.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Verdanite spear, +1" type="Magic Item" source="user.index" id="Verdanite_spear_UNCOMMON">
  <description>
    <p>This Green spear forged form Verdanite glimmers with light. While holding this magic weapon, you gain a bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it, and you gain a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls and the saving throw DCs of your druid and ranger spells. In addition, you can use the spear as a spellcasting focus for your druid and ranger spells.</p>
    <p class="indent">When you cast a spell that restores hit points, you can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the amount of hit points restored, provided you are holding the spear.</p>
  </description>
  <setters>
    <set name="keywords">spear, druid, ranger, spellcasting focus</set>
    <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
    <set name="type" addition="spear">Weapon</set>
    <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    <set name="weapon">spear</set>
    <set name="attunement" addition="by a druid or ranger">true</set>
    <set name="enhancement">1</set>
  </setters>
  <rules>
    <stat name="druid:spellcasting:attack" value="1" bonus="Verdanite spear" />
    <stat name="druid:spellcasting:dc" value="1" bonus="Verdanite spear" />
    <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:attack" value="1" bonus="Verdanite spear" />
    <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:dc" value="1" bonus="Verdanite spear" />
  </rules>
		
</element>
<element name="Verdanite Saber, " type="Magic Item" source="user.index" id="Verdanite_Saber_Rare">
  <description>
    <p>This item appears to be a longsword hilt.
While grasping the hilt, you can use a bonus action to
cause a blade of pure energy to spring into existence, or
make the blade disappear. While the blade exists, this
magic longsword shines a jade green light. If you are
proficient with shortswords or longswords, you are
proficient with the sun blade.
You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made
with this weapon, which deals radiant damage instead of
slashing damage. When you hit an undead with it, that
target takes an extra 1d8 radiant damage.
</p>
    <p class="indent">The sword's luminous blade emits bright light in a 15-
foot radius and dim light for an additional 15 feet. While
the blade persists, you can use an action to expand or
reduce its radius of bright and dim light by 5 feet each,
to a maximum of 30 feet each or a minimum of 10 feet
each.</p>
  </description>
  <setters>
    <set name="keywords">Longsword</set>
    <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
    <set name="type" addition="Longsword">Weapon</set>
    <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    <set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
    <set name="attunement" addition="by a creature proficent in longswords">true</set>
    <set name="enhancement">2</set>
  </setters>
  <rules>
  </rules>
</element>
</elements>
